MANISH KUMAR

Data Engineer | Associate

Phone: +91 < Mobile Number > email: < Your email> · Manish's LinkedIn Profile

Data Engineer with 3 years of experience in building Data Pipelines, Datawarehouse solutions, ETL, Big Data, and managing operations of multi-Terabyte systems for a Fortune 100 Pharmaceutical client.

SKILLS

• Languages: Python, SQL

• AWS: S3, EC2

 Big Data & ETL: HDFS, PySpark, Hive, Impala, YARN, Spark SQL • Repository Management: Azure DevOps

Project Management: JIRAOrchestration: CA Autosys

EXPERIENCE

APR 2020 - PRESENT

DATA ENGINEER at ZS ASSOCIATES

- Leading a DevOps workstream independently and managing a team of 3 members.
- BWAC:
 - Role: Senior Associate
 - o **Designed** and **built** a process to calculate wholesale Acquisition costs using **PySpark, SQL, and Python**.
 - Led and mentored a team of 3 associates familiarizing them on tech-stack.
- MHCDM (Data Mart cloud Migration):
 - Role: Associate
 - Delivered a project to migrate legacy on-premise processes to the cloud using Big Data technologies (Spark)
 - Actively involved in detailed data analysis using HIVE, Impala, Spark SQL, SIT and UAT fixes in the production environment.
 - Worked on **Spark performance tuning** for overall performance optimization of the process.
- Ingestion
 - Role: Associate
 - Worked on data ingestion pipeline to ingest the flat-file in the data lake.
 - Automated the flat-file loading from AWS S3 to hive table with the help of an Orchestration tool like CA Automation.

JUN 2019 - APR 2020

DATA ANALYST at STANDAV

- Analyzed more than 30,000 customer sales data to find the bottlenecks in the business process.
- Worked as Salesforce Admin and got exposure on sales cloud

EDUCATIONS

2015 - 2019

B.TECH NIT TRICHY, MATERIALS ENGINEERING

2012 - 2014

HIGH SCHOOL, SDS COLLEGE KALER (BIHAR)

CERTIFICATIONS

- Spark beyond basics (Udemy)
- Data warehouse fundamentals (Udemy)